Innovation and change are almost a given
in today's rapidly evolving marketplace.
What can organizations do to enable
change and create better experiences for
their customers and employees? Well,
hello everyone. My name is Yvonne Chan
and joining me in the studio to discuss
this topic with me today are Mr. Vikesh
Senath, the head of operations
excellence at Prudential Singapore, and
Ms. Chitra Panayik, the lead business
analyst at Capgemini Singapore. Welcome
Vikesh and Chitra. Now, Prudential has
always been an organization that puts
its customer well-being at the heart of
all that it does. And in this session,
we want to focus on what goes on behind
the scenes to ensure that the entire
organization is able to fully support
its customers in enabling groundbreaking
change and innovation. And so, I'd like
to kick us off with a question for
Vikesh about OPEX or operational
excellence. Tell us what exactly it is
and how does it enable change and
innovation within Prudential?
Thanks, Yvonne, for that question. Um
OPEX, as it I mean, um in its core, it's
basically um
something which which helps us to
achieve our purpose, Prudential purpose,
which is helping people to make best out
of their life. Um so, that's what OPEX
is all about, okay? Um
we want to really improve um the
experience of our customers. We want to
drive continuous improvement, and OPEX
helps us or enable us to do that. Now,
how does it do it? We have three pillars
of OPEX that we call it. So, the first
one is OPEX Academy, which helps to
build the capability of people and
improving and driving continuous
improvement. And second one is OPEX
Consulting, which basically helps us to
execute any strategic or
transformational projects that we have.
So, we have a pool of internal um kind
of uh
experts, right? Who who are good in
transformation and and driving change
projects. So, they are the ones who who
drives this. The third one is something
called center of excellence, which
basically drives
process automations or automations using
new technologies, okay? So, that's what
OPEX is and I mean, in summary, it is
what it is.
Um I just want to add one more thing to
that is OPEX also, whatever we do in
OPEX, it's it's about balancing three
things, okay? Number one is voice of the
business, okay? So, our
shareholders, our stakeholders, whatever
they are asking us to do. Uh voice of
the customers, so whatever our
customers' expectations from us are, and
the voice of employees.
The engagement part, okay? So, we hear
all these three voices, and through
OPEX, we try to balance this. So,
whatever we do in OPEX is basically
balancing these three voices when we
deliver it.
A very good example is in 2019, we
rolled out um a solution called Pulse,
okay? Which is a one of our mobile apps
that we rolled out. Uh it's been rolled
out in in in around 12 countries. And we
have almost have the app in like 10
different languages, and
we I think till date, we have 13 million
downloads, okay? Which which tells that
it's it's really something which people
are using, right? So, OPEX was also one
of the teams which which was working on
this uh Pulse um solution, and they
helps I mean, they basically helped to
make this a reality of translating
whatever the Pulse vision was to to
making sure that it is executed in a way
that people wanted, and then rolling it
out um into the market.
So, you talked about balancing all these
uh different components, right? Using
that one common uh company-wide
methodology, uh and also promoting this
culture, I believe, of uh continuous
improvement. Uh Chitra, uh is this one
of the common challenges that's faced by
the workforce in the insurance industry?
You know, how do you still remain
staff-centric when you're faced with a
multitude of systems?
So, yes, that is one of the biggest
challenges, right? Today, as a user, if
I have to issue a policy, I have to log
in into a legacy policy administration
system or a document management system,
communicate with my agents and partners
on emails or chats, and uh have
communications with my cross uh
departments separately.
Sounds so complicated.
Yeah, so it it adds on to your
day-to-day task. So, we are enabling
this change by building a one-stop
solution, wherein the underwriters can
do risk assessment, policies can be
issued, claims can be settled, and we
can address policy servicing requests.
One-stop solution, that's the keyword
there, right? So, you guys are coming
out with a one-stop solution to
streamline processes and make the lives
of the employees a lot easier. So, this
also frees up more of their time, so
they get more out of life. Before we
delve into that one-stop solution, I
want to come back to Vikesh and ask you
about capability building, which I know
is really big at Prudential. And given
that this year's Singapore Fintech
Festival theme centers around people and
talent development, uh tell me, why is
capable uh capability building so
important at Prudential, and where does
your OPEX Academy come in?
See, um
one thing which I'm sure everybody would
agree that as we move ahead, uh there
are certain challenges that we see,
right? Challenges in terms of the the
the speed of digitalization today, um
the the change in customer expectations,
um
external factors, pandemic, COVID, okay?
Which forces us to make those changes,
and hence
people cannot have the same capability
and drive those transformation and
changes, right? So, we need these new
skills, new capabilities, and and people
have to be ready for that, okay? And
hence, capability becomes
the centerpiece of it, okay? People
become the centerpiece of everything.
And within Prudential, uh one of our
core commitment to our people is
capability building, right? And um and
we want to do that. Um and and OPEX
Academy, how do we do it? Uh it's as as
part of the OPEX Academy, we have three
things. One is looking at the quality
part of it. So, we do it through quality
academy, which is looking at
experiences and how to improve those
experiences, okay? So, that talks about
the continuous improvement part, yeah?
The second part is the technical
academy, okay? Which looks at the core
competencies of insurance like
underwriting, claims, customer service,
and looking at where people's learning
curve are, and then trying to
kind of have programs across these
journeys where they can improve their
skills, right? So, that's improving the
core insurance skills.
The third one, which is the most
critical one, is the digital academy,
right? Everything has to be digital. And
if people have to be and be part of that
digitalization journey, um then digital
skills become very important, okay? So,
we look at certain skills which people
need for this digitalization, we try to
impart that through the digital academy,
right?
But the most important part is is the
fundamental of of this whole OPEX
Academy is it's it's not a training
program. It's a experience-based
learning, okay? What that mean is that
whatever we do, okay? We first look
internally in terms of what our people
need, right? In terms of their learning.
Whether they are processing a claim, so
they want to know more about a claim. If
they are doing underwriting, so they
want to learn about underwriting.
Process improvement, how to do process
improvement, for example. So, we take
these as training programs, we build
those training programs, and then we
when we deliver these training programs,
it is delivered through uh uh a kind of
an approach where people are not only
learning the methodology, but as we as
they go along, they are adopting it,
okay? Right away. So, what happens is um
it remains with them. Yeah, the
learnings remains with them. It doesn't
just go away somewhere, okay? So, that's
Yeah. So, that's Yeah.
So, I mean,
that's that's the whole point of uh
having that academy part, which driving
programs through people, okay? Which
they want and how they want it to be
driven. And we just I mean, it's not too
long ago we had launched this academy in
Jan 2020.
And since then, we have trained almost
like 300 to 320 people, which is sizable
number if you look at um Prudential. And
um
the feedback has been great.
I just want to get into even more detail
now, Vikesh. You know, what are the ways
does OPEX uh drive innovation, but at
the same time, still making sure that
your people and talent development
remain a top priority? Yeah, so okay.
Good point. Innovation, I think it's
it's Prudential's one of our core value,
okay? And whatever we do, um and I
talked about the purpose part of it,
innovation drives this, okay? Whatever
we do, we want to be innovative in terms
of creating solutions or creating
anything that we want both for our
external customers and internal, right?
So, in OPEX, what we did was we thought,
okay, let's create something which helps
us to look at internally, at least our
processes and everything, and helps our
own staff, our own people, right?
Because sometimes they are the most
ignored ones. Nobody looks at them,
right? So, we said, okay, let's create a
center of excellence with all these new
technologies that we hear about, whether
it is uh robotics, RPA, or AI, or
machine learning, or uh NLP's, and there
are many more technologies, right? Um
and and so, we created this COE with the
idea that, okay, let's try it out, okay?
Let's be innovative. Let's do some proof
of concept. And if it works out, let's
scale it up. Let's build that solution,
right? So, that's what um I mean, I
mean, the whole idea of setting up that
OPEX COE was. And
what happened was when we build up this
COE, we also knew that we have to work
and partner with a lot of these fintechs
and insurtechs to build and bring in
some new solutions, right? And that's
where we work with quite a lot of them.
We rolled out in 2019 itself, um I mean,
some of the solutions we picked it up,
which we rolled out in 2020, like
automating our underwriting engine. We
looked at our claims process, and we
said, okay, how do we make it far more
simpler using some of these new
technologies? And many more actually. I
mean, we have delivered quite a few
solutions using all this AI and and
machine learning processes. But, the key
one which we rolled out this year is
something called the operations
ecosystem, okay? Where we wanted to
build an ecosystem for our own internal
staff which helps them to simplify their
own life, their own processes, and look
at the processes as they want it, okay?
So, that's the automation we wanted so
that they work with one system rather
than with multiple systems that normally
people work with, okay? Yeah, makes life
a lot more easier, too. Chitra, can we
get you to elaborate on a little bit
more on how this operations ecosystem
works? Cuz I'm sure many in the audience
today would be very interested to see
how a solution still manages to be
staff-centric.
Yes. So, like Vikas spoke about having
certain objectives behind developing
this solution, and one of those key
objectives was to have an interconnected
and an iterative solution providing
real-time data for monitoring and
improvement. So, imagine yourself as an
underwriter. I have these data-driven
dashboards providing me with activity
insights and a total visibility on my
assigned tasks. I have visibility on the
SLAs which can help me meet my agency
and partner commitments. The solution is
intelligent and intuitive by telling me
where I need to focus my priorities for
the day. So, these priorities can be set
based on, for example, certain campaigns
run by agents and partners or addressing
our high net worth customer requests
first. It also provides me with the data
wherein I know how much time I'm
spending on each activity and help me
identify my own improvement areas,
right? As a team lead, I I get the
single view of the team's activity which
is especially useful for me during the
month ends when the volumes are high,
right? It helps me in load balancing and
making a well-informed decision. Uh one
of the other objectives of the solution
was to provide a rule-driven and a
data-driven workflow. Wherein I, as a
user, I don't have to be concerned about
the workload being too more or maybe the
incorrect assignments being given to me
because the logic at the back end takes
care of your role, your activities, your
capacity and availability for the day.
And one of the biggest advantages of the
solution is that it is built using the
artificial intelligence and machine
learning-based algorithms for
processing, data extraction, and
validation, and enabling to trigger
workflows having us these touchless
operations, right? So,
as a user, I get the single view of the
customer. So, the solution actually can
get or absorb content from, say, a hard
copy submission or a email or a mobile
upload, right? So, the solution being
integrated with the multiple
applications not only helps me in making
better or faster decisions, but by
predicting and identifying the
bottlenecks, I know where to monitor my
process proactively. So, it helps us
achieve operational excellence for our
customers, people, and partners. That's
fantastic. It's such a an intuitive
smart system that really enhances
productivity. And like you said, it
can't it manage it it kind of is able to
tell whether you're overloaded, whether
you have capacity or not, and
capabilities. So, on the flip side, you
can't tell your boss, "I have too much
work." Because the system would have
just allocated what you can do, right?
So, super smart. I really like that.
But, it it does also sound, guys, that
the team has achieved a lot in a
relatively short span of time. So,
with more projects in the pipeline, more
innovation expected, what what does OPEX
hope to achieve?
Um no, we for 2021, the the plan is to
even do more, um especially on improving
the staff experience, okay? Because what
we believe, um definitely in OPEX, is
that if you improve um
the staff work experience using the the
technologies which are available to
them, I think that drives more
engagement, that drives more
productivity, okay? Productivity may be
in a
in a wrong I mean, it's a wrong
connotation in a way, but I would say it
drives more engagement and loyalty
towards the organization, okay? Because
it helps them to make their life
simpler.
And then the last thing which which
which is very important for me is that I
mean, which I always believed in that if
you really have to win in marketplace,
okay? We have to first win in the
workplace. If if your people are
internally happy, they will always make
your customers happy, okay? Speaking of
your people being internally happy and
having to win in the workplace before
you go into the marketplace, I really
like that motto.
You've put your staff through three
different academies, right? Digital,
technical, as well as quality. Did I get
that right?
Yes. You see, I've been paying
attention.
So, you put them through these three
academies. What was the feedback like
from your employees? Well, the feedback
has been great. One feedback has been
the the difference they see from the
normal trainings, okay? Like in a normal
training, you have your trainer, your
slides, and your classroom or a virtual
training which happens these days,
right?
So, that's the only
the combinations that you have got, and
it's all content, content, content,
right?
You don't know whether the person who is
actually going through that training
actually understands all of that, right?
Or even takes back anything. In OPEX,
whatever we do, first of all, we look at
the real problems. We look at what
people want, our staff wants, and which
can help us to drive that mindset of
continuous improvement and improving
customer experience and all of that,
okay? So, what is the requirement first,
okay? What the people need. So, we we
take those and we develop certain
programs like in quality management or
technical or digital. Once that is done,
we develop life projects or real-life
simulations which basically people can
actually apply it while they learn it.
So, most of all the programs that we
offer, it could be a one-day program or
a two-day or a five-day program, but
most of this are delivered through an
actual project, okay? Where people can
actually adopt whatever they have
learned. And hence, they have been their
feedback has been great. They say,
"Okay, something which when I go out
even after 5 days, I will remember it
forever, okay? So, So, it's very
hands-on. Very hands-on. Right. And it's
not, like you said, just a textbook
learning that is one-sided, but it is
it's two-sided as well. Uh for a
question for the both of you then, do
you have any words of advice, you know,
for fintech firms who are
or maybe non-fintech firms who are
watching today and who might, you know,
be really impressed with how this OPEX
Academy is working, and they might want
to adopt a similar fintech solution, but
they have reservations about embarking
on this approach which is rather out of
the box. What would you say to them?
Let's start with you, Chitra.
Um I would echo what Vikas said earlier
about putting your people first at the
backdrop of having an end-to-end
transformation. So, I think giving the
key value proposition to your workforce
is extremely important um
in helping you also win your customers
and in the end, yeah. Vikas. I know.
No, I I definitely echo that. Um for me,
what is important is
um
that we talk about our customers, okay?
We talk about their ecosystem. We talk
about our distributors and their
ecosystem, but we never talk about our
people who are in the back end actually,
who are
doing the work, okay? Um and and we
never talk about their ecosystem because
they also have to work with multiple
systems and yeah. How do we connect all
of that, okay? we bring that together so
that at least we make their life even
better, yeah? So, that is something
which is very very important, right? So,
hence, we I mean, the whole point of
creating this operations ecosystem was
that how do I bring that little things
which people do using system one, two,
three, and four, how do I merge all of
this one, two, three, four into
something which not only solves their
problem in terms of the automation
problem, but also it gives them
they should feel it that this is a
system which listens to me rather than I
have to learn the solution and then do
the do the work, okay?
That's something which is important. So,
this ties back into how a solution still
manages to be a system or solution
manages to be staff-centric. And just
before we conclude, cuz I have both of
you in the hot seat right now, quick
question for you. Cuz you said, "Don't
forget the people who are putting this
together, right?" Have you been through
any of the academies under the OPEX
Academy, the digital, technical, and uh
quality Quality, that's right. Which
ones really stood out for you? Which
ones do you like?
Uh for me, a digital one is important. I
mean, all three are important, you know,
equally, but digital is important
because of the the kind of
transformation today happens, and
especially the speed of transformation,
right? Um and it's all about
digitalization, um and because of the
pandemic, because of COVID also, some of
these things have accelerated a little
bit. So, people need to learn the basic
skills of digitalization, right? So,
hence, digital becomes very important,
but equally technical, if you I mean, if
we are in insurance, so we also need to
improve our underwriting and claims and
everything. And similarly, if you have
to create new experience, then quality
becomes important, right? So, So, you
can't have one without the other. What
if right right, Vikas? What about you,
Chitra?
I I think I would go with both digital
and the technology academies because I
think it it definitely helps us do our
jobs better.
Thank you. And it does sound, you know,
so exciting, so much to look forward to.
And I do believe that, you know, the
projects that OPEX is involved in will
certainly bring about the change that is
required for an organization to stay
relevant in these ever-changing times.
You can find out more about one of the
projects that OPEX was involved in by
scanning this QR code to download Pulse.
Till next time, a big thank you again to
Mr. Vikas Sinha and Ms. Chitra Patnaik
for joining us in the studio. My name is
Yvonne Chan. Stay well, and I'll see you
next time.
[Music]